## MD AKHER ALI



## **Contact**

#### Address:

199/3 Vangapress, Jatra Bari, Dhaka 1204, Bangladesh

#### Phone:

- +8801744725107
- +8801840098721

## Email:

mohdakherali@gmail.com

#### Linkeidn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohd-akher-7ab08958

## Languages

Bangla – Native English – Fluent Hindi – Moderate

## **Summary**

A highly organized HSE Professional with more than 10 years of vast experience and great attention to detail, monitors and ensures compliance with ISO 45001:2018 standards, including health and safety statutes and regulations. Promoted safety through effective training and orientation for all project personnel. Exposer in the Elevated Expressway, Water and waste water Engineering, M&E, MRT, Architectural, Fabrication and Civil Construction Industry.

## **Skill Highlights**

- Hazard Identification
- Risk Assessment/ Management
- Safety
   Training/Orientation
- Accident Investigation
- Leadership Ability
- Health and Safety
   Management

- Conflict Management and problem-solving skills
- Communication, meeting & presentation skills
- EPC Industry Experience
- Administrative Safety policies and procedure

## **Experience**

1. Lead Safety Officer - 05/2019 to Present

SMCC-ITD JV, Dhaka Mass Rapid Transit Construction Project, Line-6 CP-06, | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Familiar with delivering safety management within a large diverse organization.
- Identifying risk and possible safety hazards of all aspects of operation & then taking action to mitigate, minimize them.
- Conducts safety meetings, audits, and inspections to ensure compliance, evaluate performance, identify corrective action, and implement follow up assessments.
- Maintain OHS standard, Implement local law & regulation on site.
- Lead and Influence a team of managers/engineers addresing daily HSE challenges.
- Develop and conduct accident investigation and implement effective recomendation
- 2. Senior Workplace Safety & Health Coordinator 10/2015 to 04/2019

#### **SANLI E&C PTE LTD | Singapore**

Manage Multiple Projects between 10/2015 to 04/2019:

- Replacement of 6.6kv and 400V Diesel Generator at 9 catchment and Waterways
- ii. Process Upgrading at Chua Chu Kang Waterworks Ozone & Biologically Activated Carbon Facilities & Civil Work (Contract 2)

# Computer literacy

Advance Microsoft Office, Excel, Power Point, MS Project, Internet browsing, etc.

## Personal Strength

- ✓ Willing to learn
- ✓ Able to engage and influence people
- ✓ Having a hands-on approach to work

## **Experience**

- iii. Equipment's Replacement at Chua Chu Kang Water Works (Existing Plant)
- iv. Pump set Replacement work at Tengeh and Kranji Pumping station
- v. Proposed EICA works for Murnane Pipeline project
- vi. Construction of Drains and Supply of Pumps at Lorong Halus Part-1
  Construction works
- Support Executive Management in the refinement of a robust HSE culture development.
- Establise the competence and training expectations HSE at all levels
- Monitoring and assessing the work of Subcontractor/third party
- Ensuring that health and safety process are established and in place.
- Oversee and review all accident investigations and analysis report.
- Define and strategize the corporate HSE plans which includes risk management and audits.

## 3. Workplace Safety & Health Coordinator - 01/2014 to 09/2015

## **Dingxin Construction Pte Ltd | Singapore**

- Develop, Review, update safety policies and programs.
- Perform job site inspections and prepare/present report.
- Organize and implement safety programs includes safe production strategies
- Liaison with authorities as required and representative of contractors and suppliers to ensure alignment and compliance
- Conduct Safety Orientation courses and job-specific training(HSE)
- Represent company in all safety-related matters

#### 4. Workplace Safety & Health Coordinator - 01/2013 to 12/2013

#### Poh Lai General Contractor Pte Ltd | Singapore

- Develop and implement safe work procedures, permit to work system compliance and hazard analysis & risk assessment implementation.
- Identify hazardous condition and make safe practice in workplace
- Promote and develop a positive and proactive Safety Culture
- Conduct Safety Orientation courses and job-specific training(HSE)
- Develop effective pre-start meeting, toolbox talk, RA briefing etc

#### 5. Site Cum Safety Supervisor - 01/2013 to 12/2013

#### Centra Jaya (S) Pte Ltd | Singapore

- Conduct Tool Box Meeting and arrange safety campaign for all stakeholders.
- Oversee and review all accident investigations and analysis report
- Manage Safe Work Practice and procedure implementation and adapting Permits To Work system.
- Ensure the development of effective Emergency response plans and coordination with Singapore Civil Defence Force.

## Core

## **Accomplishments**

- Successfully gained commitment from top management to workers at the site to get the desired HSE and production results by operating responsibly, executing with excellence, Applying innovative technologies for profitable growth inside an incident-free environment.
- Successfully strategize and led Safety Culture in the company

## Reference

Mr. Mominul Hoque HSE Manager

Dhaka MRT Line 6, CP-06

SMCC-ITD JV

Contact: 01743398768

Email: momin.cp06@gmail.com

## **Education**

Masters of Social Science: Major in Social Science - 2016

University of Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Social Science: Major in Social Science - 2013

National University, Bangladesh

## **Certifications**

- NEBOSH IGC
   NEBOSH, UK, 2021
- Fire Safety Manager
   Bangladesh Fire Safety & Civil Defense, 2021
- Advance Certificate in Workplace Safety & Health
   Workforce Skill Qualification (WSQ), Singapore, 2013
- Assess Confined Space for Safe Entry & Work
   Workforce Skill Qualification (WSQ), Singapore, 2016
- Occupational First Aid CPR+AED MOM, Singapore, 2017
- Risk Management
   Workforce Skill Qualification (WSQ), Singapore, 2013
- Managing Work-At-Height MOM, Singapore, 2017
- Work-At-Height Assessor
   MOM, Singapore, 2014
- Working-At-Height for Supervisor MOM, Singapore, 2014
- Lifting Supervisor Safety
   MOM, Singapore, 2012
- Rigging and Signaling MOM, Singapore, 2012
- Building Construction Supervisor Safety MOM, Singapore, 2012
- Fire Inspector ILO, 2020
- Plumbing & Pipefitting Supervisor
   BCA, Singapore, 2017
- Skill Evaluation Certificate in Electrical Wiring Installation BCA, Singapore, 2010